[   
  {
    "name": "Introduction",
    "description": "Learn basic words and grammar.",
    "modules": [
      {
        "icon": "child-dress",
        "title": "The verb 'lá'.",
        "lessons": [
          [
            {
              "type": "vocabulary",
              "word": "symi",
              "example": {
                "sentence": "[symi].",
                "translation": "[(a) man]."
              }
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "symi.",
              "answers": ["a man", "man"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "A man.",
              "answers": ["symi"]
            },
            {
              "type": "vocabulary",
              "word": "cévo",
              "example": {
                "sentence": "[cévo].",
                "translation": "[(a) woman]."
              }
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "Woman.",
              "answers": ["cévo"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "cévo",
              "answers": ["a woman", "woman"]
            },
            {
              "type": "vocabulary",
                "word": "lá",
                "example": {
                  "sentence": "[lá].",
                  "translation": "[He/she/it is]."
                },
                "tip": "[He/she/it] is the implied subject. If context demands it, [they] may be the implied subject."
            },
            {
              "type": "grammar",
              "description": "The verb 'lá' is at the center of most sentences in Nóri.",
              "syntax": {
                "highlight": "[interjection]",
                "sentences": [
                  {
                    "phrase": "lá cévo.",
                    "meaning": "He/she/it is a woman"
                  },
                  {
                    "phrase": "symi lá.",
                    "meaning": "A man exists."
                  }
                ]
              }
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "lá.",
              "answers": ["to be", "he is", "she is", "it is", "they are", "he's", "she's", "it's", "they're", "to exist", "he exists", "she exists", "it exists", "they exist"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "He exists.",
              "answers": ["lá"]
            },
            {
              "type": "vocabulary",
              "word": "miro",
              "example": {
                "sentence": "lá [miro].",
                "translation": "He/she/it is [(a loaf of) bread]."
              }
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "It is a bread loaf.",
              "answers": ["lá miro"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "She is Sophie.",
              "answers": ["lá Sophie"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "David lá symi.",
              "answers": ["David is a man"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "lá cévo.",
              "answers": ["he is a woman", "she is a woman", "it is a woman"]
            }
          ],
          [
            {
              "type": "vocabulary",
              "word": "kas",
              "example": {
                "sentence": "Sophie [kas] han miro.",
                "translation": "Sophie [eats] a loaf of bread."
              }
            },
            {
              "type": "grammar",
              "description": "Preverbs like [kas] are usually used before [lá], unless otherwise mentioned.",
              "syntax": {
                "highlight": "[interjection]",
                "sentences": [
                  {
                    "phrase": "David kas lá.",
                    "meaning": "David eats/drinks."
                  }
                ]
              }
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "Kiran kas lá.",
              "answers": ["Kiran eats", "Kiran drinks"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "kas lá miro.",
              "answers": ["he eats bread", "she eats bread", "it eats bread", "he eats a loaf of bread", "she eats a loaf of bread", "it eats a loaf of bread", "he eats a bread loaf", "she eats a bread loaf", "it eats a bread loaf"]
            },
            {
              "type": "vocabulary",
              "word": "mikol",
              "example": {
                "sentence": "David lá [mikol] symi.",
                "translation": "David is a [short] man."
              },
              "tip": "Adjectives come before nouns."
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "mikol symi.",
              "answers": ["a short man", "short man", "a small man", "small man"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "She is small.",
              "answers": ["lá mikol"]
            },
            {
              "type": "vocabulary",
              "word": "su",
              "example": {
                "sentence": "kas lá [milk].",
                "translation": "He/she/it drinks [milk]."
              }
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "She drinks milk.",
              "answers": ["kas lá su"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "lá su.",
              "answers": ["he is milk", "she is milk", "it is milk"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "Jordan exists.",
              "answers": ["Jordan lá"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "It is a short woman.",
              "answers": ["lá mikol cévo"]
            },
            {
              "type": "match",
              "foreign": ["miro", "kas", "cévo", "lá", "su"],
              "native": ["bread", "eat/drink", "a woman", "to be", "milk"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "A man is bread.",
              "answers": ["symi lá miro"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "A short man. A short woman.",
              "answers": ["mikol symi mikol cévo"]
            }
          ]
        ],
        "test": [
          {
            "type": "short-response",
            "direction": "foreign-native",
            "prompt": "symi.",
            "answers": ["a man", "man"]
          }
        ],
        "review": [
          {
            "type": "short-response",
            "direction": "foreign-native",
            "prompt": "woman.",
            "answers": ["a woman", "woman"]
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "icon": "handshake",
        "title": "Use personal pronouns!",
        "lessons": [
          [
            {
              "type": "vocabulary",
              "word": "ny",
              "example": {
                "sentence": "[ny] lá mikol symi.",
                "translation": "[I] am a short man"
              }
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "It is me.",
              "answers": ["lá ny"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "I am Alex.",
              "answers": ["ny lá Alex"]
            },
            {
              "type": "vocabulary",
              "word": "ké",
              "example": {
                "sentence": "[ké] lá cévo.",
                "translation": "[You] are a woman."
              },
              "tip": "[ké] can only be used as a subject (infront of the verb)."
            },
            {
              "type": "vocabulary",
              "word": "vu",
              "example": {
                "sentence": "han [vu].",
                "translation": "He/she/it is [you]."
              },
              "tip": "[vu] can only be used as a object (after the verb)."
            },
            {
              "type": "grammar",
              "description": "[ké] can only be used infront of the verb. [vu] is used in all other cases.",
              "syntax": {
                "highlight": "[interjection]",
                "sentences": [
                  {
                    "phrase": "ké lá cévo.",
                    "meaning": "You are a woman."
                  },
                  {
                    "phrase": "Sophie lá vu.",
                    "meaning": "Sophie is you."
                  }
                ]
              }
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "You are short.",
              "answers": ["ké lá mikol"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "ké lá Daniel.",
              "answers": ["you are Daniel"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "ké lá vu.",
              "answers": ["you are you"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "It is you.",
              "answers": ["lá vu"]
            },
            {
              "type": "fill-in-the-blank",
              "prompt": "lá vu. ___ lá mikol.",
              "answer": "ké",
              "choices": ["ké", "vu", "su"]
            },
            {
              "type": "vocabulary",
              "word": "téu",
              "example": {
                "sentence": "lá [téu].",
                "translation": "it is [him/her/it/them]."
              },
              "tip": "[téu] may not be used as a subject of a sentence."
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "David is him.",
              "answers": ["David lá téu"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "ny lá mikol.",
              "answers": ["I am short", "I am small"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "ké lá.",
              "answers": ["you are", "you exist"]
            }
          ],
          [
            {
              "type": "vocabulary",
              "word": "ćy",
              "example": {
                "sentence": "[ćy] lá.",
                "translation": "[We] exist."
              }
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "ćy kas lá.",
              "answers": ["we eat"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "We are short.",
              "answers": ["ćy lá mikol"]
            },
            {
              "type": "vocabulary",
              "word": "vun",
              "example": {
                "sentence": "[vun] han.",
                "translation": "[You] exist."
              }
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "You are us.",
              "answers": ["vun lá ćy"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "You all are large.",
              "answers": ["vun lá náu"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "vun lá mikol.",
              "answers": ["you are small", "you all are small", "you are short", "you all are short"]
            },
            {
              "type": "vocabulary",
              "word": "móu",
              "example": {
                "sentence": "vun kas lá [móu].",
                "translation": "You drink [water]."
              }
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "I drink water.",
              "answers": ["ny kas lá móu"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "ćy kas lá móu",
              "answers": ["we drink water"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "foreign-native",
              "prompt": "ny lá téu.",
              "answers": ["I am him", "I am her", "I am it"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "It is us.",
              "answers": ["lá ćy"]
            },
            {
              "type": "short-response",
              "direction": "native-foreign",
              "prompt": "We are short.",
              "answers": ["ćy lá mikol"]
            }
          ]
        ],
        "test": [],
        "review": []
      },
      {
        "icon": "ban",
        "disable": true,
        "title": "Negate sentences!",
        "lessons": [
          []
        ],
        "test": [],
        "review": []
      },
      {
        "icon": "arrows-to-circle",
        "disable": true,
        "title": "Use demonstratives.",
        "lessons": [
          []
        ],
        "test": [],
        "review": []
      }
    ]
  }
]